Okay, so in this section, we're going to
be talking about SWAT analysis,
right, and this other term here called a
prompt list.
So let's talk about SWAT analysis first.
Now, SWAT analysis is generally done more
at an organizational level, right?
If you use as something senior management
perform for their organization,
but it can also be done at a project level
as well.
In fact, it can be done at any level of
your organization, right?
So it can be done at a project level.
And in fact, in the
earlier video, we talked
about doing a SWAT analysis for your team.
Now SWAT stands for strengths,
weaknesses, opportunities, and threats.
So essentially what we're doing is,
in this case, if we're at a project level,
we are identifying the strengths of our
project.
What are all the strengths that we've
identified, right?
Potentially our strengths could be,
you know, we have a great team.
Right, we have a team that have worked
with each other before.
They have a team that know one another,
they have a team that work really well
together, and they're a well-experienced
team.
That's our strength.
We might identify some weaknesses.
What are our weaknesses?
Well, weaknesses might be, you know,
let's say, you know, we've got a couple of
new team members that don't have the
experience, or this is a new activity or
new project we've never done before,
right?
We don't have the experience on this.
So, you know, that could be a weakness.
But let me, don't know,
these are just a couple
of very high-level
examples I'm giving here.
Then we have opportunities and threats.
Opportunities are positive risks.
Threats are negative risks.
So what are the opportunities out there?
What opportunities do we have to finish
the project within budget, within timeline?
And then what threats are there?
What potential issues are out there?
Potential issues.
A potential issue is a risk.
So a threat is a negative.
risk.
So, essentially, then, we could be using
this to highlight some risks on our
project, right, whether it's a positive
risk or a negative risk.
And this is one of the
risk identification tools,
right, one of the ways
of identifying risks.
He could be potentially doing a SWAT
analysis, right?
So some of the strengths then could
identify some opportunities, some of your
weaknesses could identify some negative
risks, some threats.
Then you'll be utilizing
your strengths, how
we've identified some
opportunities out there.
How can we utilize our strengths to
capitalize on these opportunities?
And how can we utilize the
strengths in our team or in our
project to eliminate or reduce
the impact of a negative risk?
And then we've got these weaknesses here.
What do we need to do, how,
rather, how can we improve our
weaknesses so we can take
advantage of these opportunities?
So these are again just some analysis that
you're going to be performing.
So this is a very simple, high-level
introduction to a SWAT, to a SWAT analysis.
As I said, generally, it's done more at an
organizational level, right?
Senior management
performs SWAT analysis all the
time when it comes to
their organization, right?
It's a strategic management tool.
Now, along with SWAT,
there is another term
I want to mention here
called a prompt list.
So this is another tool that
PMI have mentioned in PIMBOC,
Another tool for identifying
risks on your project.
And a prompt list really is just
predetermined categories of risks.
So these are just predetermined
categories.
So remember, you may
potentially have hundreds,
maybe thousands of risks on your project.
So we need a way of managing all of these
risks, controlling all of these risks.
So you may create different categories of
risk.
well, there's some categories that are
already predetermined.
Now, let me just go back to the previous
slide and just talk about SWAT again.
Strengths and weaknesses are generally
internal to your organization.
So when we're talking
about an organizational level,
strengths and weaknesses
are usually internal.
For the most part, there
might be some external as well,
but normally they're
internal to your organization.
And if they're internal to your organization,
they're a lot easier to identify.
Opportunities and
threats, on the other hand,
are usually external to the organization.
Again, as a general rule,
most opportunities and
threats will be external
to your organization.
They'll be some internal, but mostly
external.
And because they're
external, they're a lot harder
to identify, a lot more
challenging to identify.
So in addition to doing a SWAT,
right, or in conjunction with a SWAT
analysis, There's a couple of other types
of analyses, right, that you might
perform, and certainly that senior
management perform.
And PMI have just listed
these as a prompt list
because these are
predetermined categories.
And these are three very
common types of additional analysis
that senior management
do, right, or you can perform.
Something called a pestle analysis,
a VUCA and a T-cup analysis.
So Pestle stands for political,
economic, social, technological,
legal, and environmental.
And this is very, very common,
right?
There's from senior management and,
you know, so in addition, or rather not in
addition, in conjunction with a SWAT,
right?
So these, if I go back, the opportunities
and threats, how do we identify
opportunities and threats, external
opportunities and threats?
You may do a pestle analysis.
That just stands for political,
economic, social, technological,
legal, environmental.
And these are all different categories of
risks.
That's something very common.
For financial institutes, another very
common analysis is something called a
VUCA, VUCA analysis, which stands for
volatility, uncertainty, complexity,
ambiguity, primarily this for financial
institutes.
And then another common one is something
called T-COP.
That's another type of analysis,
and the predetermined categories of risks
there, and where Where it stands for are
technical, environmental, commercial,
operational and political.
So these are just a
couple of additional types
of analysis that you might be performing.